the dua inside it is that
if you are a just ruler
if you are a just imam
if you are a just controller
wherever you are
you control something from
the affairs of
the generality of the people
and you do it well
O Allah be easy,
be kind with these kinds of
people
O Allah those who make things
difficult
for the people
punish them
this was the dua of the
prophet
Muhammad
and the dua has two wings
the wing of goodness
for those who rule with
goodness
and the wing of punishment
for those who are unfair to
the
generality of the people
may Allah protect us
there is one big lesson here
these days we usually talk
about
good governance, good
governance
you can see
the prophet prayed
the anger of Allah
and the punishment of Allah
upon those
who punish you
it is compulsory that any
Muslim
any Muslim who takes up
the position of leadership
maybe as a governor
maybe as a commissioner
maybe as a head of a
parastatal
maybe as a head of an agency
of government
and then you are harsh
you punish the people
there is a dua of the prophet
that will come to you because
of
your behaviour
and when you are nice
you are kind to us
you favour us
you are easy with us